Gary R. Krause

Winchester, VA | (440) 320-9202 | garyraykrause@outlook.com | https://garykrause.dev

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Exceptional record of technical leadership and effective communication in software engineering, data analysis, global information operations, and cybersecurity operations for corporations, international partners, U. S. Special Operations, and intelligence agencies. Senior Software Engineer adept at handling complex data models, diverse business logic, and critical infrastructure requirements. U.S. Senior Enlisted Leader accomplished as a strategic planner specializing in risk mitigation, technical infrastructure, and data collection and analysis. Adaptive leader of lean, agile, specialized teams. Natural problem-solver and technical visionary. Active TS w/ FSP.

- Bitcoin
- Java/C#
- Vue3 w/ Typescript
- Strategic Leadership
- DevOps/Agile Framework
- Powershell/Bash
- Project Management
- Software Testing
- Continuous Monitoring
- Systems Engineering
- Kubernetes

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer

Fundrise, Washington, DC

(2021 - 2022)

- Full-stack application developer on a team of 15 engineers, product managers, and business analysts; Hire #3 for feature development of a new internal business application used by three business units and 110 Fundrise employees to enhance their daily workflow managing a \$1 billion portfolio for +371k users; Application usage became critical to users workflow due to increased efficiency and productivity.
- Converted complex internal business logic into code; Designed complex operational data models to fit with business needs; Aggregated business data using Extract Transform Load processes; Crafted unit and integration tests to ensure the correctness of logic and discover edge cases; Used third-party web-based APIs for scheduled processing of data to improve data quality: Manually tested and reviewed peers code for quality assurance and regressions.
- Mentored and advised two junior developers in their first software engineering role via pair programming and code review; Scheduled recurring "water cooler" meetings to encourage team bonding in a remote environment.

Site Reliability Engineer II

Microsoft, Reston, VA

(2019 - 2021)

- Infrastructure engineer at a global scale working on new cloud offerings in Azure Machine Learning (AML) and O365 Enterprise Cloud for government customers value more than \$10 billion; Directly responsible for software deployments and maintenance of 1200+ services across three cloud environments involving CLI usage, configuration generation, and automated pipelines; Increased cloud availability by deploying and testing service readiness for critical O365 and AML infrastructure needs.
- Wrote services and tools for a team of 40+ engineers to cut response time exponentially to help prevent/mitigate outages; Created metric dashboards and monitoring alerts to prevent downtime from occurring for critical services; Drafted post-mortem reports to understand and direct future engineering efforts toward better reliability and security.

Tactical Information Operations Operator (Manager)

Naval Special Warfare and Fleet Organizations, Various Cities, CA/HI/VA

(2008 - 2019)

- Led teams of 2 to 25 cryptologic, cyber, and data scientists responsible for providing support to multiple SEAL Teams deployed globally. Analyzed data and networks to derive meaningful reports to guide C-level leadership and national strategic initiatives. Accountable for technical inventory valued at over \$1.5M.
- Executed 4 deployments within special operations and fleet cryptologic commands synthesizing intelligence from multiple agencies. Delivered a direct intelligence-driven impact on the course of major military conflicts via indications and warnings resulting in the collection of 26TB of crucial data for the U S Intelligence Community.
- Developed a clearly defined and compelling digital transformation for clients and international partners, leading to the acquisition of advanced 2.4GHz/5GHz wireless systems and training of 75 team members on WAN/LAN network survey, data analysis, processing, and technical reporting.
- Curated 1000+ data intercepts per day employing leading-edge cloud management tools and techniques, in addition to event mitigation, prevention, and prediction. Directly responsible for the impact and outcomes of National Security events. Extremely comfortable managing fast pace and high-growth environments.
- Acquired a lifetime of leadership, team building, and lifesaving skills, all of which lend credibility to overall technical acumen and leadership abilities

EDUCATION, TRAINING, & CERTIFICATIONS

AA, Chinese Mandarin Defense Language Institute Security+ Comp TIA